In the 1980s one partnership saved thousands of lives
The Red Sea Diving Resort is a drama, thriller,
history film directed by Gideon Raff.
Sudan, East Africa, 1980.
A team of Israeli Mossad agents plans to rescue and
transfer thousands of Ethiopian Jews to Israel.
To do so, and to avoid raising suspicions from the inquisitive and ruthless
authorities, they establish as a cover a fake diving resort by the Red Sea.
Ari Levinson, played by Chris Evans.
Rachel Reiter, played by Haley Bennett.
Sammy Navon, played by Alessandro Nivola.
Kabede Bimro, played by Michael Kenneth Williams.
Jacob 'Jake' Wolf, played by Michiel Huisman.
Max Rose, played by Alex Hassell.
The Red Sea Diving Resort (also known as Operation Brothers) is a 2019
spy thriller film written and directed by Gideon Raff.
The film stars Chris Evans as an Israeli Mossad agent who runs a covert operation to
rescue Ethiopian-Jewish refugees from Sudan to safe haven in Israel.
Williams, Haley Bennett, Alessandro Nivola, Michiel Huisman, Chris Chalk,
Greg Kinnear, and Ben Kingsley are in supporting roles.
The film is loosely based on the events of Israel's Operation Moses and Operation Joshua in 1984-1985, in which the Mossad covertly rescued Jewish-Ethiopian refugees who suffered from persecutions in Sudan in
Africa, by smuggling them all the way to the safety of Israel, using a base at the once-abandoned holiday resort of Arous Village on the Sudanese Red Sea coast, about 70km (43 miles) north of Port Sudan.
The Red Sea Diving Resort premiered at the San Francisco Jewish Film Festival on
July 28, 2019, and was released on July 31, 2019, by Netflix.
Critical reaction to the film was predominantly negative,
while audiences were mixed to positive.
The movie has been criticized for its white savior narrative.
The film explores themes of israel, mossad, refugee camp, ethiopia, sudan.
The tone is emotional and intense.